💌 diego@zzamboni.org · 🏕 zzamboni.org · 🟕 zzamboni · 🖸 zzamboni · 🚨 zzamboni · 🛗 zzamboni · 💆 zzamboni

I am a Senior Engineering Manager, IT Enterprise Architect and Researcher with 30 years of experience building systems and leading teams in startups as well as big companies. I have experience working with and leading remote teams. I possess a strong combination of leadership, conceptual and technical skills with excellent communication abilities. I specialize in the areas of Computer Security, Cloud Computing and Configuration Management.

Key skills _____

Leadership Team and project management, systems and software architecture.

Computer Security Security architecture, risk management and compliance; secure software development;

virtualization and cloud computing security; intrusion detection and prevention; oper-

ating system and network security.

Communications and Research Excellent written and spoken communication skills, with more than 30 years of written

and spoken communication, research and teaching experience.

Systems and Development Unix/Linux systems engineering and administration, system health management and

monitoring, cloud platforms (Amazon, Cloud Foundry, VMware), software development

experience (Ruby, Python, C, Perl, LISP, etc.).

Configuration Management CFEngine, Ansible, Puppet.

Languages Spanish (native), English (100%), German (B1 level).

Experience _____

Swisscom 2014 – Present Switzerland/U.S.A.

ENTERPRISE ARCHITECT AND IT CLOUDS SOLUTION SECURITY ARCHITECT

Apr 2019 – Present

- As a Solution Security Architect for IT Clouds, I am a member of the Swisscom IT Clouds leadership team:
 - I define and manage yearly KPIs and the security features and characteristics of Swisscom's cloud offerings.
 - I work with product managers, engineering teams and the corporate security group to maintain cloud platform and service compliance with internal, contractual and regulatory standards (e.g. ISO27001, ISAE3402/3000, FINMA and GDPR).
 - I established and manage the Security Champions initiative to promote and improve a culture of security responsibility.
 - I established organization-wide processes for risk management, threat modeling, audits and penetration testing.
 - I am the point of contact for CISO-level interactions with Swisscom's cloud customers.
- As an Enterprise Architect, I define future Swisscom products and solutions as part of the Swisscom Enterprise Architecture team.

ARCHITECT AND ENGINEERING LEADER FOR MONITORING, HEALTH AND STATE MANAGEMENT

Aug 2014 – Apr 2019

- Starting as a project lead and architect, I founded and led a team of up to 16 people that designed, implemented and operated the monitoring and logging capabilities for Swisscom's laaS and PaaS evolving cloud offerings:
 - Unified diverse monitoring components into a cohesive framework, reducing costs and increasing efficiency by 20%.
 - Defined architecture and implementated customer-facing monitoring and logging services.
 - Designed and implemented the *Orchard* monitoring platform for Swisscom's *Application Cloud*.
 - Defined and implemented integrations between Jira and OpsGenie for alerting of user-reported incidents.
 - Managed business relationship and implementated Swisscom-wide use of OpsGenie for alert management.
 - Managed engineering relationship with VMware for integration of their products in Swisscom's monitoring systems.

CFEngine AS

2011 - 2014 Norway/U.S.A. (remote)

SENIOR SECURITY ADVISOR AND PRODUCT MANAGER

Oct 2011 – Jun 2014

- Developed the CFEngine language roadmap and security strategy.
- Acted as overall CFEngine Advocate, with a special focus on security.
- Gave talks, wrote articles and blog posts, taught classes, and in general spread the word about CFEngine.
- Published the book Learning CFEngine (O'Reilly Media), which was used for promotion and education.
- Established and led the CFEngine Design Center project through its initial implementation phase.

September 6, 2020 Diego Zamboni

HP Enterprise Services 2009 – 2011 Mexico

ACCOUNT SECURITY OFFICER AND SERVICE DELIVERY CONSULTANT

Nov 2009 - Oct 2011

- Managed security-related topics for HP enterprise customers in Mexico and abroad.
- Initiated, advised and managed security-related projects.
- Coordinated communication among technical teams involved in security initiatives.
- · Managed all security-related aspects of the design, implementation and delivery of IT Outsourcing projects.
- Analyzed, designed and implementated solutions in the areas of system automation, configuration management, system administration, system design, virtualization, performance and security.

IBM Zurich Research Lab

2001 - 2009

Switzerland

RESEARCH STAFF MEMBER

Oct 2001 – Oct 2009

- · Established and developed research projects in intrusion detection, malware containment, and virtualization security, including:
 - Project Phantom: Security for VMware virtual environments using virtual machine introspection.
 - Billy Goat: An active worm-detection and capture system, deployed in the IBM internal and external networks.
 - Router-based Billy Goat: An active worm-capture device deployed at the network boundary and coupled with a border router to effectively and automatically spoof every unused IP address outside the local network.
 - Exorcist: Host-based, behavior-based intrusion detection using sequences of system calls.

National Autonomous University of Mexico (UNAM)

1991 - 1996

Mexico

HEAD OF COMPUTER SECURITY AREA

Aug 1995 – Aug 1996

- Established UNAM's first Intrusion Response Team, which has since evolved into a much larger organization.
- Supervised up to nine people working on different projects related to computer security.
- · Supervised and participated in the direct monitoring of the security of a Cray supercomputer and 22 Unix workstations.
- Managed security services for the whole University, including incident response, security information, auditing and teaching.
- Established the *International Computer Security Day* (sponsored by the Association for Computing Machinery) at UNAM. Acted as the main organizer of the event for two years (1994 and 1995). This event has grown and divided into the *Computer Security Day* (a one-day event) and the *Seguridad en Cómputo* (Computer Security) conference (a multi-day event).
- Designed and headed development of an audit-analysis tool for Unix systems (SAINT).

System Administrator Nov 1991 – Aug 1995

- Part of the system administration team at the University's Supercomputing Center, managing UNAM's Cray Y-MP Supercomputer and related systems.
- · Responded to security incidents affecting the Cray supercomputer and related workstations.

Education _

Ph.D. in Computer Science, Purdue University

West Lafayette, IN, U.S.A. 1996–2001

Using Internal Sensors for Computer Intrusion Detection, Advisor: Eugene H. Spafford.

Certifications_

CERTIFIED INFORMATION SYSTEMS SECURITY PROFESSIONAL (CISSP)

April 2019

SAFe® 4 Certified Product Owner/Product Manager

July 2017

Published books_____

LITERATE CONFIGURATION

Self-published 2019

LEARNING HAMMERSPOON

Self-published 2018

LEARNING CFENGINE

O'Reilly Media 2012, Self-published 2017

Research, Publications, Teaching and References _____

Available upon request.

Full Curriculum Vitæ available at https://zzamboni.org/vita/.

September 6, 2020 Diego Zamboni